Preliminary Inventory to the Polish Arts and Culture Foundation records
Hoover Institution Archives
Polish Arts and Culture Foundation records
1933-1998
2001C55
Hoover Institution Archives
42 manuscript boxes, 13 cubic foot boxes, 2 audio cassettes boxes, 5 oversize boxes, 27 linear feet (37.2 linear feet)
Correspondence, writings, printed matter, photographs, sound recordings, video tapes, and motion picture film, relating to Polish culture and history, and to the Polish community in the United States. Includes material collected by the Foundation.
Polish Arts and Culture Foundation.
Access
The collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2001.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
A private American organization for promotion of Polish culture, the Polish Arts and Culture Foundation (PACF) was established in 1966 when Poland celebrated her Christian Millennium. The Foundation's Silver Anniversary was celebrated in 1991, the year in which Poland realized the full restoration of the democratic government. PACF's mission is to educate the public about the historical, artistic, and cultural achievements of Poles and Polish Americans.
The Foundation has shared with Americans the wealth of Polish history and cultural achievements with presentations, publications, exhibits, concerts, and films. In keeping with its charter, the Foundation is a nonprofit, nonsectarian organization and engages only in nonpolitical activities.
Source: The Polish Arts and Culture Foundation website, http://www.polishculturesf.org/about/our-history/ Accessed November 5, 2012.
Scope and Content of Collection
Correspondence, writings, printed matter, photographs, sound recordings, video tapes, and motion picture film, relating to Polish culture and history, and to the Polish community in the United States. Includes material collected by the Foundation.
Motion pictures.; Phonotapes.; Poland--Civilization.; Poland--History.; Polish people--United States.; Video tapes.
- General file
  - Acknowledgements, 1979 (Box 35)
  - Notes, publications and clippings (Box 6)
  - Publications, clippings and correspondence (Box 12)
  - Publications, clippings, announcements and brochures relating to various aspects of Polish culture (Box 20)
- Alphabetical file
  - A (Box 4, 37)
  - Ada Lubowicka (Box 40)
  - American Institute of Polish Culture (AIPC) Polonaise (Box 37)
  - Alex Travel (Box 37)
  - American Council of Polish Cultural Clubs (Box 4, 37)
  - American Council of Polish Cultural Clubs (ACPCC) Convention (Box 4)
  - Architecture-Historic (Box 33)
  - Architecture-Modern (Box 33)
  - B (Box 35)
  - Benefit for Medicine and Food for Poland (Box 39)
  - Berezowska, Maja (Box 35)
  - "Big Band" Katowice (Box 35)
  - Book donations (Box 35)
  - Brachel, Jolanta (Box 35)
  - Bruser, M. (Box 35)
  - C (Box 35, 36)
  - California State Board of Education (Box 36)
  - Carnoy (Box 36)
  - Cavanaugh (Box 35)
  - Cepelia (Box 35)
  - CETA (Comprehensive Economic and Trade Agreement between Canada and the European Union) and H. Kubica (Box 35)
  - Children's Health Center (Box 35)
  - Children's Theater TV (Box 14)
  - Church-Religion (Box 33)
  - Clippings in English and Polish (Box 1)
  - Concert, Feb. 28, 1981 (Box 36)
  - Copernicus (Box 35)
  - Correspondence re concerts (Box 3)
  - Czestochowa (Box 14)
  - Czestochowska (Box 14)
  - D (Box 14)
  - Donat, Z. (Box 10)
  - Drake, Anna (Box 36)
  - E (Box 14, 36)
  - F (Box 14, 15)
  - Fashion show (Box 15)
  - Faulkner, W. (Box 15)
  - Fedorowicz (Box 5)
  - Film (Box 7, 9)
  - Film Festival, 1972 (Box 15)
  - Film lists (Box 15)
  - Film list of educational films available through the Polish embassy (Box 1)
  - Film list of films available through the Polish Arts and Culture Foundation (PACF) (Box 1)
  - Film showings (Box 15)
  - Films and work notes (Box 15)
  - G (Box 5, 15)
  - Gdansk Choir (Box 15)
  - Genealogical research in Poland (Box 15)
  - Glynn case (Box 5)
  - Gogolewska (Box 15)
  - Grabianowski (Box 5)
  - Grotowski (Box 5)
  - H (Box 5)
  - Halka (Box 38)
  - Hulanicka (Box 38)
  - I (Box 5, 38)
  - J (Box 5, 38)
  - Janks, Mrs. S. James (Box 38)
  - K (Box 5)
  - K (Box 38)
  - Katyn, 1903-1940 (Box 2)
  - Klene (Box 38)
  - Kobielska (Box 38)
  - Kopernik w oczach dziecka (Box 6)
  - Kopydlowski (Box 6)
  - Kord, K. and I. Nawe (Box 10)
  - Kosciuszko (Box 8)
  - Kosciuszko and Pulawski (Box 7)
  - Kosciuszko Foundation (Box 40)
  - Kosinski (Box 38)
  - Kossak, W. (Box 7)
  - Kowalczyk, Jan (Box 6)
  - L (Box 38, 40)
  - Leszyk (Box 40)
  - Lissowska (Box 40)
  - Lizakowski, Adam (Box 40)
  - Lorentz (Box 10)
  - Lutoslawski, Witold (photographs and printed matter) (Box 7)
  - M (Box 10, 40)
  - Malarecki, K. (Box 40)
  - Manuscript of a book of reminiscences (Box 2)
  - Matejko, J. (Box 8)
  - Mazowsze, Slask (Box 7)
  - Miko (Box 40)
  - Millennium (Box 33)
  - Mitera, Zygmunt (Box 2)
  - Movie script, post-production (Box 2)
  - Mrozewscy (Box 40)
  - Murasowa (Box 40)
  - N (Box 40)
  - National Museum of Women (Box 10)
  - O (Box 13)
  - Oakland International Festival, 1978 (Box 13)
  - Oakland Museum, work notes and publicity (Box 13)
  - Ochman, W. (Box 10)
  - Opera (Box 10)
  - Osmanczyk (Box 2)
  - P (Box 13)
  - PACF San Antonio (Box 13)
  - Paczynski (Box 13)
  - Panna Maria Texas (Box 13)
  - Penderecki (Box 9)
  - Pilsudski (Box 7)
  - Pola Negri (Box 10)
  - Polish Radio and TV (Box 2)
  - Polonian (Box 9)
  - "Polska" Mobile (Box 12)
  - Popielarczyk (Box 8)
  - Pope John Paul II
    General note
    See also box 27
    - Cardinal Karol Wojtyla and his elevation to the papacy as John Paul II, publications, clippings, and photographs, circa 1976-1999 (Box 17)
    - Photos of Pope John Paul II (Box 15)
    - The Pope's Visit to San Francsico (Box 12)
    - Pope John Paul II visits to Poland in 1979 and 1983, publications, clippings, photographs, and programs (Box 16)
    - John Paul II, publications and photographs, circa 1976-1999 (Box 18)
    - John Paul II and other aspects of Polish culture, publications and clippings (Box 19)
    - Pope John Paul II publications, including a Marvel Comics comic book about his life. Also included is a publication about Stefan Cardinal Wyszinski (Box 32)
    - Oversized photographs relating mainly to the papacy of John Paul II and other aspects of Polish history (Box 41)
  - Postcards-Pre World War I (Box 9)
  - R (Box 12)
  - Refugees (Box 12)
  - Requests (Box 2)
  - Reynolds, R.M. (Box 12)
  - ROHO (Box 12)
  - Ross-Raszplew (Box 12)
  - S (Box 2, 11)
  - Satanowski (Box 3)
  - Sociology (Box 7)
  - Solidarity Santa Rosa list of confined Solidarity activists as of Feb. 15, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Szczygielska (Box 3)
  - Szymanowski (Box 9)
  - T (Box 11)
  - T, correspondence (Box 11)
  - Tadeusz Kermer (Box 38)
  - Tarnawska (Box 3)
  - Tatarkiewicz, Wladyslaw (Box 6)
  - Tatarkiewicz (Box 3)
  - Tereszczenko (Box 11)
  - Theater (Box 3)
  - Theater and Cabaret (Box 7)
  - Theater, "The Jeweler's Shop" (Box 34)
  - U (Box 34)
  - University of California (U.C.) Berkeley
    - U.C. Anthropology (Box 34)
    - U.C. Archives (Box 34)
    - U.C. Art Museum (Box 34)
    - U.C. Associated Students (Box 34)
    - U.C. Calendar (Box 34)
    - U.C. Design Department (Box 34)
    - U.C. Drama Department (Box 34)
    - U.C. Faculty Club (Box 34)
    - U.C. Lawrence Hall of Science (Box 34)
    - U.C. Library (Box 34)
    - U.C. Music Department (Box 34)
    - U.C. Slavic Language and Literature Department (Box 34)
  - U.S. Health, Education, and Welfare (Box 3)
  - United Nations Association (Box 34)
  - United States Department of State (Box 34)
  - V (Box 34, 39)
  - Visa forms (Box 3)
  - W (Box 3, 34)
  - Wajda festival (Box 15)
  - Wanda Rut (Box 9)
  - Warsaw Symphony (Box 39)
  - Warsaw Uprising 50th Anniversary (Box 8)
  - Warsaw-Royal Castle (Box 33)
  - Wigilja (Box 39)
  - Women of the Year (Box 39)
  - Z (Box 39)
  - Zanussi (Box 9)
  - Zawojski (Box 39)
- Printed matter
  - General printed matter (Box 8)
  - Publications relating to Polish art, film, and education (Box 22)
  - Polish history textbook for sixth graders, 1954 (Box 36)
  - Polish language textbook, 1972 (Box 39)
  - Children's Polish language textbook, 1972 (Box 40)
- Photographs and pamphlets
  - Agriculture (Box 29)
  - Army (Box 29)
  - Art (Box 31)
  - Children (Box 29)
  - Churches (Box 23)
  - Concentration camps (Box 30)
  - Education (Box 31)
  - Fashion and design (Box 21)
  - Film (4 folders) (Box 23)
  - Folk Art (Box 31)
  - Folk traditions (Box 21)
  - Folk traditions-costumes (Box 21)
  - Foreign heads of state visit Poland (Box 20)
  - Government (Box 30)
  - Health care (Box 30)
  - History - Before 1800 (Box 29)
  - History - Ninteenth Century (Box 29)
  - Horses (Box 23)
  - Industry (Box 30)
  - Industry-shipbuilding (Box 30)
  - Kennedy, Robert in Czestochowa (Box 23)
  - Literature, 19th century (Box 21)
  - Manors (Box 30)
  - Milosz, Czeslaw (Box 29)
  - Music-classical (Box 21)
  - National costumes (Box 21)
  - Nature, Environment (Box 31)
  - Pilsudski, J. (Box 29)
  - Polish Americans, Polish emigres (Box 29)
  - Popular (Box 30)
  - Royal castle (Box 21)
  - Scientists (Box 23)
  - Sienkiewicz, H. (Box 29)
  - Sport (Box 23)
  - Stamps (Box 21)
  - Theater (Box 31)
  - Tourism, Recreation (Box 29)
  - Vilnius (Box 21)
  - Warsaw (Box 29)
  - Warsaw Royal Castle (Box 31)
  - World War II (Box 30)
  - World War II Children (Box 29)
  - World War II historic monuments (Box 30)
  - Writers (Box 29)
  - Zamenhof, L. (Box 29)
- Sound recordings (Box 24-25)
  Conditions Governing Access note
  For information on getting a use copy, please contact the Hoover Institution Archives
  - Polish musical and cultural events in Poland and the U.S. (64 compact sound cassettes)
    - "Prof. Bartoszewski's Lecture at Polish Arts and Culture Foundation (PACF)," parts I and II, April 16, 2984 (Box 24)
    - "Prof. Bartoszewski's Lecture at Polish Arts and Culture Foundation (PACF)," part III, April 16, 1984 (Box 24)
    - "Convention of Polonia (in Poland)"
      - 1974 (Box 24)
      - 1975 (2 compact sound cassettes) (Box 24)
      - 1976 (Box 24)
    - "Dedication of Lech Walesa Street in San Francisco," October 3, 1986 (Box 24)
    - "Farewell to Irena Tolstoy" (Box 24)
    - "Jacek Fedorowicz" (Box 24)
    - "History of Poland" (2 compact sound cassettes) (Box 24)
    - "History of Poland, Heritage Seminar" (3 compact sound cassettes) (Box 24)
    - "Interview for Polish Radio in Paris, France," June 16, 1982 (Box 24)
    - "John Paul II Gateway Records GSLP 1303" (Box 24)
    - "KABL, W.T. Citizen of the Day," August 14, 1977 (Box 24)
    - "KQED Polish Program" (5 compact sound cassettes)
      - "International Congress of History, Sworakowska with Lerski," September 21, 1975 (2 compact sound cassettes) (Box 24)
      - "Lerski, New Underground" (Box 24)
      - "Zakrzewski o ZNP," September 28, 1975 (2 compact sound cassettes) (Box 24)
    - "Ksztalty Soli," film (Box 24)
    - "Profesor Jerzy Lerski," March 29, 1992 (2 compact sound cassettes) (Box 24)
    - "Mauthausen," film (Box 24)
    - "Milosz Poetry Reading"
      - 1968 (Box 24)
      - 1977 (Box 24)
    - "Moczulski" (2 compact sound cassettes) (Box 24)
    - "Janusz Onyszkiewicz at PACF," September 23, 1989 (Box 24)
    - "Jan Pietrzak" (Box 24)
    - "Piwnica Pod Baranami. Marek Grechuta," 1981 (Box 24)
    - "Kabaret Pod Egida," January 15, 1981 (Box 24)
    - "Podroz Magiczna," film (Box 24)
    - "Polish Cultural Hour - Lech Walesa" (Box 24)
    - "Polonaise Ball, 1983. Message to Lech Walesa" (Box 24)
    - "Polska 5, 6" film (Box 24)
    - "Polskie Skrzydla" film (Box 24)
    - "Powstanie," film (Box 24)
    - "M. Raczek" (2 compact sound cassettes) (Box 24)
    - "Reminiscences of Poles," May 25, 1978 (2 compact sound cassettes) (Box 24)
    - "Sacrosong Festival" (3 compact sound cassettes) (Box 25)
    - "Sawicki," October 5, 1975 (Box 25)
    - "Seminar - Poland Today" (Box 25)
    - "Semper Fidelis" (Box 25)
    - "Serce Batiara" (Box 25)
    - "Sercem Spiewane" (Box 25)
    - "B. Simpson with Jane Curry," January 2, 1989 (Box 25)
    - "Skrzydla nad Baltykiem", "Raport w Sprawie Miasta" films text (Box 25)
    - "Songs of Solidarity, Gdansk, August, 1981" (2 compact sound cassettes) (Box 25)
    - "Prof. A. Stelmachowski" (Box 25)
    - "Tuszewski at PACF Interviews" (2 compact sound cassettes) (Box 25)
    - "Basia Wachowicz - Ja Jedna Znam" (Box 25)
    - "Zakrzewski" (Box 25)
    - "A. Zygmunt" (3 compact sound cassettes) (Box 25)
  - "63 days", 1/4-inch sound tape reel with soundtrack of the film (Box 57)
  - "Constitution of May 3rd," 1/4-inch sound tape reel (Box 57)
- Video recordings
  - Video recordings mainly relating to Pope John Paul's fourth and fifth visits to Poland and America, 20 VHS tapes
    - "Pope John Paul II in San Francisco, Mass, September 18, 1987" (2 VHS tapes) (Box 26)
    - "Pope John Paul II, San Francisco, Sep 17-18, 1987" (3 VHS tapes) (Box 26)
    - "Pope in America," September 1987 (Box 26)
    - "I Come As a Pilgrim," John Paul II in America, 1987 (Box 26)
    - "Pope in Monterey," September 17, 1987 (Box 26)
    - "IV Pielgrzymka Ojca Sw. Jana Pawla II Do Ojczyzny," June 9, 1991, Warszawa, Part I and II (2 VHS tapes) (Box 26)
    - "IV Pielgrzymka Jana Pawla II do Ojczyzny; Spotkanie z Wojskiem/Koszalin 02.06.1991, Rozpoczecie Synodu/Warszawa 08.06.1991" (2 VHS tapes) (Box 26)
    - "IV Pielgrzymka Jana Pawla do Ojczyzny - 09.06.91 Warszawa" SECAM (Box 26)
    - "John Paul II. The Pope From Poland," narrated by James A. Michener (3 VHS tapes) (Box 26-27)
    - "In God's Country," KPIX (Ch.5) interviews from Poland, with translations, 1987 (Box 27)
    - "Wroclaw Miastem Kongresu" (Wroclaw - the Congress City) (Box 27)
    - "V Pielgrzymka Papieza do Polski" (Box 27)
    - "Europa Nadziei Jan Pawel II," with English subtitles, 60 min (Box 27)
  - Video recordings related to Polish cultural events and performances, 18 VHS tapes
    - "The Prior of the Pauline Monastery on Jasna Gora in Czestochowa, during his visit in San Francisco on October 26, 1986. Painting of the Black Madonna of Czestochowa." (Box 27)
    - "Ojciec i Syn," Professor Zbigniew Brzezinski and his family, directed by Zbigniew Kowalewski, 66 min. (2 VHS tapes) (Box 27)
    - "Lviv, 27, 28" (Box 27)
    - "Kiev, Lviv" (Box 27)
    - "Lech Walesa St.," October 3, 1986 (Box 27)
      DVD use copy, color, sound. Use copy reference number: 2001C55_v_0009339_r01
    - "Profesor Koj na Uniwersytecie Stanford," November 7, 1984 (Box 27)
    - "Artur Rubinstein," historic film of Rubinstein in performance, "Kultur", 74 min. (Box 27)
    - "Chopin Foundation 1" (Box 27)
    - "Wizyta G. Bush'a cz II," SECAM; "Bal San Francisco," PAL (Box 28)
    - "Poland, July 1985" (Box 28)
    - "Personnalité à Domicile" Joanna Bruzdowicz - portrait, Belgian TV, 1992 (Box 28)
    - "American Dreams" (Box 28)
    - "Dr. Rodger Bick," of University of Texas. Bick receives Hon. Ph.D. from the Medical Academy in Bialystok, Poland (Box 28)
    - "Polonaise Ball, November 16, 1996, Fairmont Hotel, San Francisco, CA" (Box 28)
    - "St. Joseph's Day" parade from St. Joseph's to St. Patrick's in San Francisco, June 1994; "Schindler's List," premiere in Krakow (Box 28)
    - "Walesa in USA," 1989 (Box 28)
  - Video recordings related to Polish history, culture, military, and education in the 20th century, 15 VHS tapes, 2 U-matic videocassettes
    - "Madame Curie" (Box 28)
    - "Telegraph," premiere episode, February 4, 1989 (Box 28)
    - "Swiatowy Zjazd Lotnikow Polskich Orle Gniazdo,'" 1992 (Box 28)
    - "The Enigma Secret," by Roman Wionczek, 158 min (Box 28)
    - "Kroniki Powstania Warszawskiego. Sceny z Powstania Warszawskiego" (Box 28)
    - "To Know Where They Are," Anti-Defamation League, the Joseph H. and Bell R. Braun Center for Holocaust Studies, September 25, 1990 (Box 28)
    - "All the People Polish Contributions," recorded in 1975, U-matic videocassette (Box 57)
    - "Gorlice" (Box 57)
    - "Cracow and Its University" (Box 57)
    - "Historia Polski. Kronika Warszawy na Tle Wydarzen 1900-1939" (Box 57)
    - "Polish Contributions to America," W.T.s' TV program on Channel 2, November 10, 1975. One hour, U-matic videocassette (Box 57)
    - "Z Calego Swiata. Zjazd Polonii i Polakow z Zagranicy" (Box 57)
    - "Zbrodnia Katynska" (Box 57)
    - "Od Legionow na Wawel. Marszalek Jozef Pilsudski" (Box 57)
    - "Bo Wolnosc Krzyzami sie Mierzy. Gen. Anders i Jego Zolnierze" (Box 57)
    - "Sztuka Krolewska Czyli Rzecz o Wolnomularstwie" (Box 57)
    - "Kultura of Paris. Interviews with Polish Writers" (Box 57)
- Motion picture films (Box 42-54, Film shelf Film shelf)
  - "Bystrzyca Region," 2 reels, 600 ft. and unknown length, 16mm film and sound (Box 42)
  - "Drzymala's Wagoon," 16mm film (Box 42)
  - "Marek i Malgorzata," 1200 ft., 16mm film (Box 42)
  - "Mauthausen," 1000 ft., 16mm film (Box 42)
  - "Monte Cassino," 16mm film (Box 42)
  - "The Castle," 600 ft., 16mm film (Box 42)
  - "300 Years of the Wilanow Palace," 500 ft., 16mm film (Box 43)
  - "Ensemble 'Silesia'," 1200 ft., 16mm film (Box 43)
  - "Inside the Royal Castle," 450 ft., 16mm film (Box 43)
  - "Jan Parandowski," 16mm film (Box 43)
  - "Naleczow," 375 ft., 16mm film (Box 43)
  - "Pultusk - Polonia seat," 400 ft., 16mm film (Box 43)
  - "Rogalin Palace," 16mm film (Box 43)
  - "The Guard's Change," 800 ft., 16mm film (Box 43)
  - "Maria Kuncewiczowa," 1300 ft., 16mm film (Box 44)
  - "Mr Colonel's Eagels," 1000 ft., 16mm film (Box 44)
  - "Peasant-Poetry (W. Daruk), 800 ft., 16mm film (Box 44)
  - "Profesor Brach," 450 ft., 16mm film (Box 44)
  - "Profesor Zachwatowicz," 1300 ft., 16mm film (Box 44)
  - "Solo to America," 750 ft., 16mm film (Box 44)
  - "Good Morning Captain!," 1000 ft., 16mm film (Box 45)
  - "Jan Mulak-trener," 800 ft., 16mm film (Box 45)
  - "Stella Walasiewiczowna W Polsce," 800 ft., 16mm film (Box 45)
  - "The Wroclaw Experiment," 390 ft., 16mm film (Box 45)
  - "Tolm on the Way of the Eagle's Nests," 900 ft., 16mm film (Box 45)
  - "Birthplace," 750 ft., 16mm film (Box 46)
  - "Karkonosze Mountains," 2 reels, 600, 350 ft., 16mm film and sound (Box 46)
  - "Poland in the Lens #1," 800 ft., 16mm film (Box 46)
  - "The Report on the City," 1100 ft., 16mm film (Box 46)
  - "U ujscia Dolry," 750 ft., 16mm film (Box 46)
  - "A Letter from the Holidays in Poland #1,R," 2 reels, 16mm film (Box 47)
  - "Gniezno '79," 700 ft., 16mm film (Box 47)
  - "Homo Varsoviensis," 16mm film (Box 47)
  - "State without States," 2 reels, 700, 1100 ft., 16mm film and sound (Box 47)
  - "The Polish Wings," 550 ft., 16mm film (Box 47)
  - "Warsaw 1977," 950 ft., 16mm film (Box 47)
  - "Z. Stanczyk" labeled bag includes "Poland at War," "Poland, the Land and its Products," "The History of Poland," "The People of Poland," "Poland's Culture, Customs and Traditions" and two others, 7 reels, 150 ft. and various lengths, 16mm, 35mm film (Box 47)
  - "Poland (#17)," 900 ft., 16mm film (Box 48)
  - "Poland in the Lens #12," 1050 ft., 16mm film (Box 48)
  - "Poland in the Lens #2," 800 ft., 16mm film (Box 48)
  - "Poland in the Lens #3," 800 ft., 16mm film (Box 48)
  - "Ready for a Parade," 16mm film (Box 48)
  - "Poland (#18)," 600 ft., 16mm film (Box 49)
  - "Poland (8)," 800 ft., 16mm film (Box 49)
  - "Poland from the Air," 800 ft., 16mm film (Box 49)
  - "Poland in the Lens #13," 16mm film (Box 49)
  - "Poland in the Lens #14," 16mm film (Box 49)
  - "Poland in the Lens #9," 1000 ft., 16mm film (Box 49)
  - "Poland (VI)," 725 ft., 16mm film (Box 50)
  - "Poland in the Lens #22," 16mm film (Box 50)
  - "Poland in the World," 16mm film (Box 50)
  - "Poland Nr 5," 600 ft., 16mm film (Box 50)
  - "Poland Today Part 1," 2 reels, 400 ft. and unknown length, 16mm film and sound (Box 50)
  - "Poland Today," 16mm film (Box 50)
  - "General Wladyslaw Sikorski," 2 reels, 16mm film (Box 51)
  - "KPIX #1,#2,#3," 1000 ft., 16mm film (Box 51)
  - "KPIX #1,#2,#3," 1150 ft., 16mm film (Box 51)
  - "KPIX #1,#2,#3," 575 ft., 16mm film (Box 51)
  - "Poland #15," 710 ft., 16mm film (Box 51)
  - "Polonia Is Marching On," 750 ft., 16mm film (Box 51)
  - Unidentified film, 16mm film (Box 51)
  - "H 27-2," 900 ft., 35mm film (Box 52)
  - "H 27-3," 950 ft., 35mm film (Box 52)
  - "Pod znakiem #1 GEI-historia lekow," 1100 ft., 16mm film (Box 52)
  - "Podhalanczycy," 900 ft., 16mm film (Box 52)
  - "Polish Montmorency," 16mm film (Box 52)
  - "Roots," 500 ft., 16mm film (Box 52)
  - "For Liberty Ours and Yours," 2 reels, 1000, 900 ft., 16mm film (Box 53)
  - "H 27-4," 425 ft., 35mm film (Box 53)
  - "H 27-6," 975 ft., 35mm film (Box 53)
  - "H-27-1," 1000 ft., 35mm film (Box 53)
  - "H-27-5," 775 ft., 35mm film (Box 53)
  - "Memory," 1200 ft., 16mm film (Box 53)
  - "We Give You Just Memory?" 650 ft., 16mm film (Box 53)
  - "From Westerplatte to Berlin," 1000 ft., 16mm film (Box 54)
  - "The Clergy Martyrdom," 1050 ft., 16mm film (Box 54)
  - "Bohater Dwoch Narodow," 800 ft., 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - "Children and Students," 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - "Dzwieckowy," 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - "Himmler Operation Part 2," 2 reels, 1000, 1500 ft., 16mm film and sound (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - "Homo Varsoviensis," 1800 ft., 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - "John Paul II The Pope from Poland," 1800 ft., 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - "Looking back at Rzeszow Wspomnienia z Rzeszowa," 800 ft., 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - "November's Insurrection," 1200 ft., 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - "Palace in Lancut," 425 ft., 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - "Poland (7)," 900 ft., 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - "Poland in the Lens #11," 1200 ft., 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - "Poland in the Lens #4," 800 ft., 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - "Poland Today," 2 reels, 550 ft. and unknown length, 16mm film and sound (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - "Pope's Homeland," 3 reels, 1200 ft. and various lengths, 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - "Skarby Jasnej Gory," 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - "So That Man May Understand Man," 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - "The King's Come Back," 1000 ft., 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - "The Mouse," 2 reels, 1500, 1000 ft., 16mm film and sound (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - "W Kosciolach Polski (In the Churches of Poland)," 1100 ft., 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - "Wielkopolska," 1000 ft., 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - "Wings over Beskidy Mountains," 700 ft., 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)